welcome to credit chats where we deep
dive into the financial Maze and uncover
how everything from your daily coffee to
your dream home impacts your credit
score I'm learon and thank you for
joining us each episode will explore the
ins and outs of personal finance here
from experts and answer your questions
so tune in take notes and transform your
financial Journey with us let's get
started welcome back to credit chats
everybody I am Lear your host and we're
doing a new segment called just the tip
where I give you a a credit tip today
our credit tip is did you know keeping
your credit utilization below 30% of
your credit limit can make a huge
difference in your score credit
utilization is the ratio of your credit
card balances to your credit limits and
it's a major factor in calculating your
score the lower it is the better curious
about this impact on your score long
term do some digging watch your credit
improve significantly by managing that
balance to limit ratio
all right we are here with Joe Fels and
he is the high energy person that I've
been talking about to all my friends so
Joe welcome
man glad to be here you man so let me
read this bio because because this is an
amazing story you have man so it's no
secret Joe fails is a uniquely creative
mind a proven record of profit and stays
outside the box more than masking tape
he is a Serial entrepreneur heading up
eight separate llc's annually uing the
norm at every step Joe renounced most of
his personal possessions in August 2022
moving from a 3500 foot home to a 1999
Dodge van equipped with little more than
a pair of American flag shorts his first
homemade solar generator and a dream
after a seven-year Hiatus he reactivated
his Tik Tock to Chronicle his journey
from Millions to minimalism having grown
up without a TV Joe is a technological
Neo
having never posted a video much less
recorded and edited one he was standing
there in cargo shorts trashing a
three-year-old Android for his first
iPhone his mom asked him what are you
gonna do with those videos and he said I
don't know I'll save up and maybe I'll
sell them on Netflix or something and
the rest is history thank you Joe for
accepting the invitation being here
again we met on the blocks and I love
your story man I love your transparency
and and we connected so thank
you and I want to say hey I loved your
story your energy and your intention
which is a lot of people everybody's in
business to make money but you're in
business to help people and therefore
make money which is I'm in the same
industry as you might say and you sent
me somebody the other day that that was
that had some that wanted some help with
his credit and and we talked about 45
minutes and very little of that was
talking about credit so it it was it's
amazing and the kind of people that you
draw around you are the same heart and
you have the biggest heart I have ever
seen in anybody so thank you man little
man big heart you are a big man man I
tell you though man but that's what
people don't understand is that they
always they're always at step two or
three and they need to be at Step Zero
on everything and most people think
they're trying to to make a profit right
but in in order if you're going to be an
entrepreneur in order to produce a
profit you have to to to refine a person
and they don't understand that they're
over they they they already asking her
to go home with them and he ain't even
bought the lady a
drink oh great analogy man great analogy
can you share a little bit about your
journey from being incarcerated to
becoming a successful entrepreneur and
what was that Turning Point like for you
dude it's such a complex story I
remember the journey home dude I
remember my dad came and picked me up my
dad oh I'll
cry and dude when I was released on
8910 I went outside and I remember it
was in McCormack South Carolina because
I paroled from prison to a felony
detainer and when they they released me
I went outside and I just grabbed
handfuls of of of leaves off the forest
floor and I was out in the woods was out
in the middle of nowhere and I just
remember the smell of
outside and you think about that was 14
years ago last month and now
God
damn yeah man business is business it
just started with a with an idea
everything starts with an idea and if
you see me here overseeing millions of
dollars of Revenue in vast companies all
of them started with with an idea just a
simple idea you're waiting for a train
that will take you far away and the way
we we translate those ideas into into
reality is you have to see it in your
mind first before it comes out and when
you said you you grabbed a handful of
leaves and you smelled it people don't
understand how much something as little
as that can mean so much to somebody who
didn't have it and and the reason I know
that is because I went overseas with the
military but I wasn't military I was I
worked for DOD but something as small as
the way the water smells when you don't
have clean water is something you don't
know that is is a thing for you until
you get it back it's amazing to hear
like that that one little and the smell
of rain is one thing I love too it's
just
wow man you you should come run with me
in the old growth forest of the
p&w spruce and fur and Cedar that are
hundreds of years old and
there's hey let me tell you one other
thing completely off topic but I I
believe this would be pertinent to you
when I was in prison I taught myself
Greek and I translated two of the
gospels from Greek into English cuz I
wanted to really understand it this is
how I do everything if you want to
understand something you have to go down
to the smallest block the not the atom
the Quark I'm talking about we're going
because everything is a microcosm of the
next the Quark to the atom to the cell
to the tissue to the organ to the human
to the ecosystem to the Earth to the
it's just built business and everything
is the same way but if you're reading
the Bible the New Testament every time
you see the word Numa you see the word
Spirit every time you see the word
spirit in the New Testament the word in
Greek is Numa P NE ma it's where we draw
pneumatic and pneumonia it literally
means breath yeah and now you have now
go through the New Testament and replace
spirit with breath and you have a book
on
yoga and ever heard the phrase Lost in
Translation yep and a lot of the people
that are that are teaching on the name
Yahweh doesn't have any syllables in it
it's the name of God is when you breathe
in and breathe out so that's the
name that's it so you're the first thing
you say is and the last thing you're
ever gonna
say man people don't they the answers
have been there whole your whole life
they've been telling you they were there
they were telling you God has been
broadcasting since you were born your
antenna has not been correctly tuned
he's still doing it and like I said pay
attention to little things and this will
go back to business because the way you
do anything is the way you do
everything and I understand business
like I understand the natural world and
how I understand the the spiritual world
at this point and I I'm going to tell
you just to observe what's going on God
talked to Isaac with a ram he talked to
Noah with a dove he talked to Ezekiel
with a fleece Moses
and these people this what I'm saying
and but here's the thing how many times
have you seen a bird streak across the
sky and not thought anything of
it that's the thing God is still talking
we're just too distracted with the
things around us like The Giving Tree
we're grown up we don't have time for
you we want VR and we want food and we
want this no man I am intimately
connected with the world around me every
time I have a good idea and I'm talking
to somebody and I see an eagle streak
across the sky I time it
is every time man like it's little
things and that's what I'm saying Above
All Things seek wisdom and recently I
had to slow down just because I was
going doing too much and and I say doing
too much not in the sense of I shouldn't
be doing this but more so in the sense
of I wasn't taken in the journey so if
you see this right here that was where I
got a let let me move was it over was it
an elbow over top closer there I see no
I I was working out was elbow over no I
was working out and I passed out and I
hit my head on a a metal pole that just
just just got me to thinking like okay I
need to be taken in the scenery because
I I was so focused on the destination
that I wasn't looking at the I wasn't
looking at the scenery so that was one
of the that was one of the ways got man
that's part of it driven and he'll do
that to you hold on that that's Jacob's
laugh okay yeah okay it used to be a pot
leaf it was the first tattoo ever had I
got it covered when I was in prison you
know why I got that on
there cuz Jacob was hard-headed and he
ran from God remember he was so
hardheaded he slept on a rock and had a
dream and an angel that was going up and
down and the
angel Jacob fought the angel and it hurt
his hip Jacob didn't care who it was
Angel friend and he was hard-headed but
then he woke up his hard-headed ass woke
up and said the Lord was with me and I
knew it not the whole
time yep and there's always been
something there man we get so focused on
the doing that we don't we're not
being man to quote Bill Wilson you need
to have your feet firmly planted on the
ground and your head in the
clouds you know a very good quote
because you're of this it's a ying and
yang man you're supposed to H you in
this modern world you have to have money
but you're damn sure not supposed to
love it you're actually supposed to
revile it as a necessary eil yeah it's a
tool you know like driving a car I hate
burning gas but I see no other way to
exist in the planet as it is right now
yet working on it all right on to what
inspired you to move from your house to
to be a nomad that that lifestyle to
where you live off the land and I follow
you so I see all of the stuff that
you're doing that that you do for free
and I love it and so what inspired you
to do that
in August of 22 that's it was 12 years I
got out of prison I won't give you the
backstories massive spiritual experience
at six months
later I was just sick dude I'd done
everything Society had told me to do I
gotten out I stayed sober for 13 years I
I got married I had kids I started
businesses I ched meetings in the same
psych W where I was locked up twice for
a 4-year period I was a pillar in the
did all everything I won Ultra marathons
and I was [__] miserable I remember I
had a shoe box or a Georgia boot with
$120,000 in cash in my closet and was
just an empty shell of a human and I
lived on a big house in a say six and a
half acres with a barn big live oak
trees a swing from my daughter that I
gutted and reconfigured House of our
literal
dreams empty and I was just is miserable
and so I literally said [__]
it [__] it I'm gone just like like the
Samoans they just go out I'm going lash
some trees together out in the night sky
dude I bought a house of in out on the
west coast my Sea Shack it was all
[__] up and I drove all the way this
van I just drove out there to go remodel
my house without any idea man I started
writing a book on the way I met Alex
like a week in on Tinder driving through
the West through the Midwest and I
didn't know it I was running from I was
running from the pain of society and the
system and just the
extreme imprisonment I felt like I've
been out of prison and they it's like
they let you out of the prison and now
you're in The Truman Show [__] Hunger
Games
2.0 is I got out of the main prison now
I'm in this one I can't do anything I
just want to be left alone
and when I went with that I didn't
realize I thought I was just going to
retire like [__] this I make a large
amount of residual income and I only
have three mortgages I do very well
financially I own around seven
properties and I just I didn't realize I
couldn't just quit because you were
forever responsible for that which you
tamed and over the last two years I've
been
overseeing eight businesses from this
van on this starlink that you're talking
to me on right now and it has not been
easy yeah running a seven fig
Construction Company remotely
is I about to say it's tough
anywhere so you just add on so here's
what I but here's I did not intend for
this but here's what happened is I was
forced to innovate
solutions to make things work forced and
you've seen me live I be in some wild
ass places doing some wild ass things
you can't the first time I left they
didn't know if I was alive or dead for a
week I went out in the woods I didn't
have starlink nobody knew where I was
for three days and I went on a seven
mile trail run up a mountain and went up
on a glacier and then I was gone on this
Glacier all day and that's how I am and
so it's hard to run a lot of massive
Enterprises when you like to live like
this but in order to do it you have to
establish
systems and here's the thing I realized
last winter that I that the problem was
not me it was all the people up under me
he could not figure out what the [__]
I'm telling him and it's a communication
error because our brains think
differently and I always say I don't
know how to tell you something except
with words dog and you have to do I tell
you steps and they don't see them as
steps they're like oh yeah oh hey I say
send an email with this information when
we get off the phone four days later I
get an email with some other information
and I blow the [__] up and you can ask
anybody in my company or Richmond County
government that I have a Timber so it
wasn't good for company morale or my my
blood pressure and I had to find ways to
make people do right and so in essence
what do you think I did I want to show
you how our my brain thinks as compared
to a normal person's how do you think I
began
building these systems and figuring out
how to I guess what I would do was look
at look at the stuff that I'm doing
day-to-day and then start making
playbooks around the things that I do
day to to offload it to other
people so listen remember how I told you
everybody's at step two or three I'm at
Step Zero or negative one do you know
what I
did I consumed every piece of literature
I could on
paleoanthropology and
Humanities what I wanted to do was
understand human nature at its core at
its core and I started doing that years
ago and then over this drive I listened
to a number of Old West historical books
I never read novels Wyatt her ride the
devil's herd and then books on the
creation of AI starting in 2000 BC with
a man named hurus because what I needed
to do was understand how Humanity thinks
and what motivates Us and how it has
changed in digital age so I had to go
all the way back to see what the curve
of the human mind looked like and now it
went like this to be honest with you
it's down here now FYI we a bunch of
dummies we used to hunt woolly mammoth
for a survival dog and now you need a
safe place with the words don't hurt you
and when you go on some they ask you
what your PR is
yeah I just if I could just put
Spartacus every time I should but
anyways and then once I understood how
the human mind worked I needed to
understand how the robot M worked
because how the [__] can you understand
how to blend two puzzles together if
you've never even seen them and so I
mean I was just foreign to me and so
what I did is I went in there and I read
all of
this and over the last started in
December I've been crafting this app to
run my Construction Company remotely and
my renovation company and I did not
understand what I was building when I
started man
but I've built a [__]
Behemoth I really have it's four panels
in one it has an admin panel a manager
panel a vendor panel and a client panel
linked directly to QuickBook it has
built-in accounting built-in reports man
it has task management and Lead
management with monetization penalties
if they're late not just a slap on the
wrist it has change order management it
has contracts in app um and and the way
it's structured is there's no fluff a
lot of these apps I looked at do [__]
like if you yes if you run a 10 billion
dollar commercial construction company
and have nine point extras in the office
this might be great but if you just a
dude trying to work on houses you don't
need all that no what I did is create
the
algorithm for the most efficient way to
complete a construction project manage
your employees and track all your finan
with single action triple entry wow
that's the main thing I cut out all the
fluff and that that's big because when
you're doing construction or when you're
flipping houses or whatever you're doing
there's so many levels of of reporting
that you have to do at any point the
admin can click a button and get a print
out of every an Excel spreadsheet like
eight pages every dollar in every dollar
out every estimate given every invoice
paid broken down and in the
in inside project management I have a
material management section that falls
within the specification of a specific
job on a spe or on a specific project
like the cabinets on 98
millage and so people instead of receipt
management is hard where you got they
want pictures they the IRS dude they
[__] suck but they want all this so
but I okay you make these dumb ass rules
I'll read them and figure out a way to
do it bet and so what it is material
Management in my contracts a lot of
people use my Lowe's card because I get
great discounts and it's they don't have
to come out of pocket to buy material
we're all happy and
so I have a section there where you
upload the picture of the receipt where
it was bought how much it was and a
little bit what was in there all that
goes into a file it's saved in the cloud
so you can literally track all of your
materials your permits every dollar use
and I made it so broad it's not like
QuickBooks where you have to have this
no dude you can save them in here and
you can have a file that you export to
your to your VA to sort if and file by
thing but it's all saved one time and
this is what I'm saying with one action
we do three
things okay with this the one action is
having the person who buys the
material enter it how do we hold them
accountable in their contract it says if
you buy anything on my card you have to
just tell me what you bought that's fair
if you don't you're responsible for that
amount until I get the
receipt I've built teeth in everything
to make PE to make them act right but
once they enter that it automatically is
logged and it goes into the cloud so we
have all the receipts so that's two
steps and then the third one is it goes
into an Excel spreadsheet so it runs it
and we can always tell how much we're
spending you can catch overtures before
they happen and the way I have a a
pretty specific bid process that's
different than everybody else's and I'll
just tell you it begins with a
guest yeah I'm excited to see it
whenever you do release it because it's
gonna it's going to change a lot here's
the other thing anybody who has a
tangible service a barber a mechanic a
tattoo artist a Jewelry Artist A anybody
could use it because of the way it
functions pictures you want a price you
send me pictures in a description I'll
send you a guesstimate and that what is
that it's literally a ballpark range to
see if there's any chance we're going to
do business and this is twofold because
the client that's all they want often
times on a home how much does it cost to
build a bathroom I don't know and then
on the vendor side we're always going to
[__] dead end jobs that's the biggest
time least of Tire kickers and here's
what I've solved that in the first step
of my funnel wow to bring a to get
everybody on the same page and that
funnel goes like this boom and with
built-in contracts and built-in payments
man it's streamline there is at every
step if you're not serious you're
getting off this train it's half live
now and it's going so it's two panels
the webbased panels are live now and the
other ones are live I don't know if
you've ever developed an app or tried to
get an agency App
Store nope but I will be talking to you
I keep people keep telling me that I
need to have my own credit app because I
I understand this stuff really
good and hey I'm going to I'll say this
on a pop how much do you think it would
it cost to develop I would think it was
in like the at least the tens of
thousands yes a lot of people spend
upwards of $100,000 to a 250 to develop
a good app what I built is four apps in
one I got teeth in this guy you know
what I mean and yeah dude it's been a
lot man but I could probably I now have
a team that just works for for me I
hired him I found him it took me a while
we've been working together for 10
months his the app developer's dad died
and he was on a call five hours later
that's how dedicated these people are
and if you want one built I could tell
you how to go about writing down the
concept to get a quote because that's
yeah and we'll talk about it offline um
just for the sake of us doing business
together but but yeah this goes right
along with the line of question anyway
CU you you're in real estate right now
and solar energy so so what Drew you to
these two two things to align your
passion with sustainable
living
solar I've always been interested in
solar it's fascinated me why it's
getting something for nothing and it
it's coming
down for free every
day and like I said a three-fold
decision every time we put a solar panel
on the roof I live in Georgia dog you
put a solar panel on the roof it absorbs
the sunlight that is normally hitting
your black shingles and making your
house hotter and so it reduces the heat
coming in and then it converts it to
energy that you can use to cool your
home this is known as exponential growth
meletus and so I've always like been
interested in when I got this van I had
to make it solar and I didn't know
anything about it at all and I went down
the same Rabbit Hole everybody online
and I think it's purposefully confusing
that way you buy a bunch of [__] you
don't need and there's so much there's
I'm not going to say misinformation but
disinformation out there that's just
skewed enough to be confusing or too
high level for a normal person to
understand and solar is really so easy
man but three-fold decision I love it
free energy two freedom I have a mobile
power plant in my van I have not had to
pay a power bill for Joe Phils in over
two years
threefold did you know that solar
qualifies for a 30% solar tax
credit so not only are you not
paying interesting thought did you know
this you can roll them forward for 20 TR
I did not know
that so the question would be this in my
copious free time I spent lots of hours
on obscure government websites Lots
reading obscure opinions and notes and
it's a rabbit hole but they write them I
read them and I basically found out how
I can in the state of Georgia Carolina
be even better because they have a
25% state tax credit on top of it so 55%
tax credit in Carolina but ideally look
at
this I could take a riddle property that
I
have and spend x amount of money to put
so let's say $50,000 to make it a
complete offset with a battery backup
right okay so if I do that without going
into all the rules you can write off 85%
of that in the first year as
depreciation as an expenditure okay then
you can take advantage of the 30% solar
tax credit which would be
what
$15,000 something like that yeah okay if
you take 85% of of 50 Grand or and then
30% of that man you're really walking
away with $23,000 right there just in
your first year dep appreciation and
that's big when it comes to to house
prices and purchase prices and all of
that stuff well but then let me spin
this for you a little bit further
because you're a financial guy right I
said a three-fold decision that's only a
one twofold right then you know what I'm
going to do Georgia has net metering
that's great they pay you a third of
what they sell you power for so what I'm
gonna do
I'm going to rent my property with
electricity included and I'm going to
sell the power
first wow my house yeah I have a battery
backup and you know what else I can do I
can set my batteries and my inverters to
give all the power during the heat of
the day and and then run and discharge
and then guess what even if my batteries
Get Low I can have my inverter charge
the batteries on the grid when it's off
peak at 3 cents k hour so I'mma [__]
beat them at your own game dog all you
got to do is slip the jab and come with
an overhand W and hit him in the liver
that's it and lastly here's two other
things that are from the Mind well one
in Georgia your average appreciation is
4.4% if you put solar on your home I am
hedging that in the next five years as
grid gets more unreliable and people
realize and know what I know about the
unavailability of Transformers and the
inability of the power companies to make
their wires any
bigger people who have these homes are
going to Skyrocket in value very quickly
and at that time the price of solar
equipment will do the same so if you're
getting in now you're literally ahead of
the curve uh and then the last thing is
that net metering does not pay you a
whole lot depending on how big the
system is and how it's engineered and
the Energy Efficiency of the home and
all this [__] you probably make make
between 50 75 bucks a month selling
energy back to the Grid in Georgia but
that's good that's a little bit of money
right say the average power bill is $140
a month and say lnd you made $150 a
month $50 a month off of your energy so
if you increase your monthly income by
$200 and with all your tax incentives on
a $50,000 purchase you're really only
out of pocket like 22
Grand and you're make
that dude that's your 1% right there man
you're making 10% off your investment
every month it's it's killer so and you
can generate renewable energy credits
for each megawatt of energy you put back
into the grid which is a commodity that
very few people even know exists that
can be sold to Big
polluters so and hey and here's the
other thing I I'm not even done if you
use panels made in America with aluminum
mine in them that's another
10% uh tax right off we can keep going
dude in business and this is what I'm
telling you most people in business are
only making onefold
decisions now you see how I've gotten
where I've gotten in such a short amount
of time is Once Again to quote my man
Bill Wilson good is often enemy of best
man you taking home a 7.5 because you
don't think you can hit a
10 and that's what I'm telling you is
above all things you have to be good at
thinking
dog that's it and you see how we think
through something and the only issue is
there's absolutely no playbook for it it
h it's like artwork it literally has to
begin in your mind and exit your mind
the things you notic in the trends and
patterns and so trying to teach people
how I understand business is a challenge
cuz if you can't tell it's different I
keep talking about weird obscure things
but I'm really trying to teach you how I
have been suc
bu and it's weird man is it kind of
strange I mean it's not common but at
the very least I do understand where
you're coming from with it though
because because when you get back to
rudimentary things that's when you
understand like when you build the
blocks on it and that was that's that's
a lot of the the reason like when I went
to the blocks I I pulled back my
business because I didn't understand the
rudimentary level things of business of
how to build it on top of each other and
if I wanted to build it um more stable
than I had to get back to the
basics hey chop wood carry
water chop wood carry water chop wood
carry water hey the message is If any
man not work let him also not eat a
little sleep a little Slumber a little
folding of the hands to rest so shall th
poverty come upon you like a thief in
the night and your need like an armed
man consider man and when people most
people are out there doing what we would
call mindlessly grinding they're working
their ass off but they don't understand
and it's like fishing You' be out there
fishing in a part of the lake and
there's no fish there and the other
option is you're fishing in a part of
the lake where there are some fish but
there's a [__] ton of
people and all of you are using the same
typ bait maybe a different color and but
here's the thing man there's another
part of this Lake you most people don't
know it exist why because you got to go
up this little windy ass
a big
ass and yeah and there's a you're not
allowed to go on this path by the way
there's government agents all along you
have to do do Dodge and and I once you
get there though man there's a lot of
fish and you're not going to see anybody
else but because the path you took there
and it seems like all the government
agents that are lined in front of it
they're just giving you fish to to keep
you away from going there so they give
you this little piece of fish they give
you this little piece of fish and you're
like okay yeah cool I'll go back to my
mindlessness and they're keeping you
away from doing it
yourself they do not want you to be
independent oh my God that's their
biggest fear is people who are
independent and
self-reliant and do not need them and
also see them for what they are a coward
with a badge Who convinced himself that
he was something and then you believed
they're thieves really because they're
taking all of your hard- earned money
and if anybody else did the same thing
they were doing
they be locked up did you see what
happened in Canada I just I live in a
cave some dude in Canada massive
protests they hey they're sitting down
in Canada dog it's happening France
they're throwing [__] and hay on the
floor of parliament dude people and
here's people are fed up and here's the
thing in the age of Technology you can't
keep us in the
dark hey let me show you
something I'll be right back I'm going
to show you how what I mean by the cat
has been let out of the bag and they've
told you it's happening hold
on a
sticker check this
out what's the symbol for apple
apple why is that significant I don't
know apple with what a bite out of it
[Laughter]
what the answers have been there all
along you just have been looking too
high you got to get primitive
dog the knowledge of Good and Evil we
know it's out we have let it out of the
bag information is is there and also
evil and it will never be put back in
most successful tech company in the
world I've asked many people about this
emblem and nobody has understood what I
was about to tell them until I told
them and that times 10,000 has led me to
believe that I have a very unique mind
not smart just observant observant is
Buck I'll be on a trail run I'll stop to
pick up a down a mountain and fli oh
there's a beetle there no little tiny
things and think about them and uh the
business journey is you know I love it
because it's
challenging and I have never in my life
been challenged like I was this summer
Alex and I did so much [__] that we have
never ever done in my life uh I've been
on obscure websites with people in
foreign countries on calls that always
begin at 11:30 p.m. on Amazon World
Services Mongol DB Play Store I've been
given API key sandboxes I have no idea
what I've been doing dude I've been set
up encryption keys to FAS bro I've gone
from Joe Dirt to Jason
Bourne and we built websites and we know
how to do [__] now and starlink bro it's
like man if a bomb could go off and the
power could go out in I'd be just fine
as long as satellit still work and the
things we learned about systems and
structure and Humanity especially at the
blocks and mindset and culture and all
these keywords you hear talked about in
high corporate circles I understand them
now God I get them and I can't wait I'm
not really eager to go back to a ghost
but I can't wait to go to go revamp my
company again yeah and give my people
the ability to step up and give them
basically the idea is that I want them
to be able to do the same amount of work
in a third of the
time that way they can do whatever they
want with the other third
they can they can make more money they
can spend time with their family and
write a book they can travel whatever
they want to do I want people to I want
people to be happy especially my I have
to start with a test run but I have this
strange theory
that that the unhappiness of humanity is
what's destroying planet
Earth
Yep you did you get there think about it
why are they cutting down the rainforce
right now to grow
beef cuz so so they can earn money we
don't need any more beef in America look
at
us come on man it's just Jesus Christ we
have 1.9 billion pounds of cheese in a
cave in Missouri just in case what the
[__] we have so much and and but why
they think that money will make them
happy and really at a core level people
just want to be happy and they have been
improperly programmed with a fatal flaw
in their mind that says money won make
me happy and I can assure you that the
first time you get a million dollars in
your hands have you ever had that yet
you're not in cash now okay I'm not here
the first time you have it you know
what'll
happen the exhilaration of having it
will immediately be replaced by the fear
of losing it dropping below that seven
figure Mark
and the
instant thought of how I'm going to make
the next
one but
the dude it's the it's worse than a it's
worse than a love affair a Nick buzz and
a cocaine High combined it's the biggest
lie of your [__] life and I might be
the only person saying it but I don't
give a [__] ask anybody else as an
entrepreneur look at them they have
billions and they're trying to get more
they're caught they're hooked but they
don't know it they don't know it and
they let the money him man look at
Zuckerberg Liv he [__] kicked out all
these people in Hawaii Facebook bringing
people together and kicking [__]
people out so I can have more land for
me yeah but but somebody I follow his
name is Julian Gordon but he he always
says you don't really want you don't
want money you want the feeling that the
money brings you when you have whatever
that thing is that you have so you want
the feeling you don't really want the
money step go back three steps I'm
telling you every every single thing you
you I want money why because I thought
was told money would make me
happy and that's the thing man that's
why everybody is doing this and think
about it man like people are always
worried about the economy and if you and
it is more American than European you
ever been to
Europe
Spain I I spent three weeks with Alex in
a van touring the architecture of Spain
the castles and
Cathedrals and in Spain they come in
around eight or 10 I don't know and you
know how at Waffle House you see a bunch
of guys pulled up drinking coffee all
the time old man bro in Spain you'll see
the same thing oxygen tank cane and
they'll have three open bottles of wine
at 9:00 a.m. and they're talking hanging
out and then everybody goes home at 121
for Siesta so basically they wake up and
do a little bit of something hey and
everybody's drinking wine a lot I'm not
saying I'm not saying that to say
they're alcoholics but that's the mind
they're just relaxed and they eat a
little food and then they go for a walk
everybody walks everywhere and then they
go home and they take a nap and then
they come back out
at five or eight like there's no D set
time and then they open up and they'll
start the kitchen when the help gets
there and serve you drinks and it's a
social culture and the motivation for
money is secondary
and people are happier and there's kids
on all the parks I did not see an
overweight child the whole time I was in
Spain and I thought I was like wow like
like why can't we have this type of
existence anywhere and I know I'm I know
that's a highly the government over
there is the EU and it's large and in
charge too but the whole mindset of the
people is different and here's what I
found tying back to
business customer service and quality is
how you will make it and most people are
just worried about making the money no
dude worry about this and do not ever
think about the money until the job is
done
well and the money will come right and
the most successful business is they
don't sell products they sell
feelings man yeah look at only
fans they said they made more than the
the whole NBA combined hey boy they s
that t
feeling facts hey and I had something
that I wanted to tell I I remembered
[Laughter]
it he wants to be on on the podcast
too you would not believe a rock anab
smoke wheel Chase it flies out of your
Buzz pretty well that's what the natives
used to
I any native
so I believe
I you're more native than a lot of
people yeah dude I have Aladdin live
right now I'm digging I but I have very
good credit I've always my entire life
the first time I ever checked
it I was going for a line of credit for
the first time ever and I never checked
it and she told me I came back and I had
an
805 and I went I was like oh I was like
okay I was trying to get approved for a
line of credit I
thought exactly what I thought I needed
a thousand I was like damn that's a B
minus that's almost a
c no that's an
A but I had been in prison
before and here's what I'm fitting I'm
fitting to give you some game for
anybody in prison
what happened to me is when
I was out there living in the streets is
I was living in this hotel with a guy
named Eric Mueller I hope you can watch
it I've been we done reconnected a
little bit and he he we were living in a
hotel and Eric have my CR I bought the
first hotel night and Eric just kept
going down there he man I'll get the
next one he just said hey keep putting
it back on the card and I didn't know
and I was on the run from the law like 3
or 4 months later and it was a I don't
know 2,000 credit card bill and I took
off uh and left and I had this big
credit card bill and Bo when I flipped
my car the insurance money came in and
my mama took it and paid my credit card
off and I got out of prison I didn't
know it but I had a 783 credit score the
minute I got out of
prison and so here is what I'm going to
tell
everybody if you have somebody in prison
get a credit card for them and you just
live off of
it buy spend all of your monthly bills
on it and pay it off in full every time
and if you do that when this individual
gets out of prison they might not have
any money but they'll have good
credit and that is huge apartment ah
he's got some felonies he's got almost
an 800 credit score he'll pay the bills
that's what I'm saying and I'm sure it's
the same thing with your kids it's the
same thing with your
kids wow see when they're eight yeah
Roth IR a same thing so you put them on
you put them on your credit you give
them as long as you're using your credit
for good purposes and then when they
turn 18 you get them a credit card but
you use it until they're responsible
enough to use it on their own and it's
going to shoot their credit score up so
when they finally do be able to buy a
house they'll have good credit here is
the hustle that I have conceived I'm
working on it now Alex's kids the
13-year-old girl is probably the best
video editor I I have she helps me now
she gets them closer to what I want than
anybody else and hey if you can I don't
care how old you are you can't do it but
what I can do is Fels Media Group can
hire Alex hoskinson on a subcontract
basis right and here's the deal we'll
give you this and a third of the money
is going to go in your pocket kid
congrats a third of the money is going
to go to buy your
groceries fair you live here and then a
third of the money is going to go into a
Roth IRA
and if I ran the numbers if we got a 5%
Roth IRA right now uh when Charlie was
25 in 12 years she'd have $777,000 in
taxfree
cash and know how to use
it Maj part right there they we have
taught you to fish your 25 you know what
you can do with 77 Grand kid you can buy
a property and now you know how to fix
it I done taught you and we have an app
you can
line refi and then you whatever can
invest you can buy a business you can
start a business you can build a van you
can buy another house and refi you're
off on your own all of those skills are
marketable skills you have video editing
you have rehab skills you have Financial
skills that people don't know all of
that stuff is marketable and you can
help all the other people because
they're going to come to you and say
how'd you do this and all you have to do
is tell them how you did it and they'll
pay you for it
check this out ver I can get a job
anywhere on planet Earth the first day
without an application or a drug
screen any country any language because
I can fix things and because I know how
to do almost everything required in life
from a lot of different spheres I'm not
a medical doctor but I haven't been to
one in over 12 years and I was a
competitive Ultra Runner I know how to
fix myself I know how to eat properly
like I have I know how to forage I know
how to catch fish clean fish fix cars
build houses navigate through the woods
castles and this is what I was telling
you dude Above All Things seek wisdom be
good at thinking but yeah the so that's
the same thing with Solomon um he he
asked for wisdom and everything else he
was given and
and you said
Solomon I identify with that man more
than of them David's my guy my name is
Joseph David now look
here the story of David I'll tell you
man I have the blood of David in me but
do you know d the story of David do you
understand it like I understand probably
not because you take it
back well bro check this out Baron David
was probably 13 or 14 he wasn't in the
army boy I will cry man younger than all
his
brothers I feel Ste these in here dude
and I draw so much power from them
because people have been doing this [__]
for Millennia and they left you a
Playbook and it's incumbent on you to
understand the evidence of Things Not
Seen and the substance of things hope
for and man once you do dude you'll tap
into a source of power that is Limitless
and they've been telling you this [__]
for years and you haven't understood the
assignment but everything you need is
inside of you and that's all what this
is about
hey you can never believe in your in God
you can never believe in God if you
don't believe in yourself because God is
within you
yep wow and that when how does that
pertain to this is business you know why
check I'm gonna tell you how David
pertains to
business and this is pretty interesting
let me preface this by saying I learned
this in the AI books do you know how
algorithms work and what makes them so
in
intelligent um they I think I I can I
can attempt this but they they learn
from your
behaviors we're gonna go down a little
bit further algorithms are considered
intelligent because they can quickly
correlate very different concepts
through very obscure
commonality right Jesus called them
Parables dog the afterlife and fishing
so you know David in business all right
it's a beh it's a giant this is where I
identify with David man I'm a nobody I'm
a kid right and David heard this dude
run in his mouth and he was like bro who
is that and you read the Bible but think
about what he was really saying you've
been in the street before he wasn't
talking no oh thee thou he was saying
come on you [__] made [__]
yeah he was like hey y'all y'all gonna
let him talk like
this what what
challenge The Establishment I don't care
how big it is and then they said kid if
you're going to fight this fight this is
the armor you need and David went in
there and they gave him this
fancy pled armor and he said what the I
can't even walk yeah this is not me ding
ding I feel the other thing about that
is that was the king's armor and I would
my question would have been like why
isn't the king why doesn't he have it on
he wasn't out
there you got a bleep button
this is an explicit podcast he this what
I'm saying the king is a coward he will
not fight but David said I'm and so he
said bro get get this off of me I'm F to
go to down in the woods and what David
and David trotted off down to the stream
right and imagine what they were saying
up there somebody taking beds I mean
think about it bro this hey guys after
he gets his head go ahead and get your
bags ready we going home over under 2
minutes method of death they was how
what hey and David he did not listen to
the static you know why he understood
the assignment like he told Saul I see
this machine yeah it's a bigger machine
but guess what I understand this system
just like the wolf that took the sheep
and the bear that took the sheep and I
know I'm drawing from a source of
inspiration he said I'm drawing God will
deliver me just like he did this and
then David went down how many rocks did
David pick up
five picked up five smooth Stones look
and he went out there and everybody
thought David was
insane but David knew exactly what the
[__] to do and he only need one rock to
prove it now he took five he was ready
for five rounds and I'm going to tell
you the establishment if you're
listening Goliath was not studying that
Pebble neither Cletus nope
coming for you man it that's what I've
been saying now and and where I am with
the regulation and the government it's
the same exact structure as street gangs
prison gangs exactly same exact
structure but they're not as good at
what they do they don't accomplish
anything like the the J get [__] done
they balance a
budget so yeah man but the story of
David
dude and then think about the Journey of
the man and you were to say something
about Solomon I didn't want to derail
you from that no okay dude can you tell
this the book is written on my heart
yeah and tattooed all over my body yeah
but Jesus's hands bed it's inspiring and
if you look at it and you parallel it to
your life you can overcome a lot of
things and just just with the story of
David alone like we often times forget
how many times God has brought us out
and we have amnesia for those things and
we're like God are you going to do it
are you going to do it I know he's check
my record
hey you know what I realized this is
what happened man my whole life dude
when we when I ran away from the law
that night we flipped that car twice I
didn't have a scratch on me before we
took off the last thing I saw I getting
up put out the fire and I saw two
shooting stars and I was just like huh
interesting back then I didn't
understand later it made sense hey when
I was in prison I worked at the law
library then I got a job in inside
maintenance hey my name happens to be
Joseph David by the way I W I was
blessed in prison I I got to steal the
kitchen every day we had a gym in the
boiler room I worked out in and
everywhere I've gone I've been protected
and and why I've been through so much
[__] in my life man oh boy remember one
time I hid
naked under a dock holding onto a pile
on in the water while the police walked
on top looking for
me I was 20 one years
old I had been in the streets for two
years at that point man and I was just
like why why but hey just like I tell my
kids when I spank them or make them run
another lap I got to make you tough kid
because my job is to prepare you for the
world in which you were about to enter
not the world as I wish it to be sorry
this is The Grapes of Wrath kid and I
got to prepare you for it and man think
about how that pertains to the stress of
business
what's he what's been your biggest
challenge in business um my biggest
challenge in in business is getting out
of my own
way o yeah
o
so the entrepreneur how does it
different how does the entrepreneur
differ from the business owner the
entrepreneur differ from the business
owner see hey we got to go back a little
deeper so the difference basically a
business owner becomes an entrepreneur
when he realizes that he is both the
bottleneck and the Lynch pin to his
success basically a business that an
entrepreneur runs
entrepreneurially he could die and the
business would keep
going why because he structured this
business with systems and trained a team
he built a machine out of his head
with no Playbook and then train people
how to run his unique machine and use it
to generate profit in the same way that
a real clever native would have taken
rocks and put them in the river in order
to make the salmon come right here to
the Gill
Zone and then trained instead he just
built this machine and then what he said
is hey buddy you want some salmon I'm
going to teach you how to you just got
to stand here and I'll give you three
out of every 10 you
kill and then he goes and buys a buffalo
and converts it to a solar powered band
and and does what he want you see the
difference but the business owner he has
found a great part of the river and
learned how to fish it really well and
he knows how to kill them and he makes
killing doing it but the thing is he's
making a killing and then he he gets
this fish and he's he he has a whole lot
of fish and what's he do he gets a w
three wives because he's got so much
fish and he has more mouths to feed and
he's still a phenomenal fisherman but
there's only a he can only catch so
many and if he then one day he twists
his ankle and his spear breaks and
there's no it's limited to his own
ability he has not let me teach you
something from Star Wars dog you always
have to have an
apprentice because if you think about it
that's the only way information has been
transmitted throughout Millennia
properly is by observation and
imprinting and so part of the reason the
trades are so bad construction and
Manufacturing is because there's nobody
actually taking the time to learn the
whole process they just learn what
somebody else feels are the most
pertinent parts of the process in order
to quickly produce a cheap product in
order to make the most money and profit
motive has really ruined quality in
America and and everywhere profit motive
has ruined health care it's ruined
education it's ruined college football
[__] dude it's ruined pretty much it's
ruined the forest the Arctic Circle the
drilling oil out of the ocean like it's
just like [__] man yeah and that's a lot
of the reason that I switched my credit
model to education more so than just
trying to fix it for people cuz when you
fix it for people you don't Empower them
so when you teach it when you teach it
to them you Empower them to to repeat
this repeat it over and over it's a
repeatable um outcome so my goal isn't
to to fix credit and have people come
back to me so they can keep paying me
that's not my goal
my goal is to empower people to
understand credit so that they can use
it
effectively very yeah you don't want to
give them a fish you know why because
they'll eat that fish and they'll be
hungry they'll come back they'll have to
keep coming back that's a good business
model man I I want to help people and if
I help you then pay me because you're
going to go make some money off of this
and to this point I've never taken a
dollar from anybody from for
coaching and do you think I would make a
good bus
coach real estate I mean anything I
wanted to coach I could man but I just
feel I feel bad taking people's money to
just tell them something that was freely
taught me that I have made Millions off
of and it has a good message because
like what I keep telling people is that
it if you want to make money you need to
try to learn how to make yourself happy
and other people happy
and that's a whole different vibe than
in NBA yes you have to learn systems yes
you have to learn structure man but most
everybody in Corporate America has a red
lightsaber dog we need somebody with a
green one you know that that's the
difference man I and I know there's
other people out there man but I don't
know anybody else with as many things in
business and as much Capital as I have
living a completely minimalist
lifestyle dude I haven't taken a shower
in a house other than when I was at the
blocks maybe four times since I left in
on June
11th I've used the bathroom outside in
the woods 95% of my time I literally
live what I'm talking about man and I
found that not only can I make more
money but it forces me to innovate
solutions that will make my business
better that's a not my primary
motivation but that's a definite
tangible outcome in your fixing see it
when his damn app is dude so EXC see it
this is goes right along with my next
question anyway you're known for helping
people so what drives that desire to
give back and how do you incorporate
that into your business model what funny
every question you ask me I give a
Biblical to like that the bible really
good Concepts in it but but here's the
thing they're the deepest Concepts on
planet Earth it's a
spiritual guideline and people think
about that it's a
guideline it is that basic bro no you
know how many people breathe all day
long and never even consider the fact
that they're breathing we literally call
them mouth breather for a reason though
that's they're so ignorant of their
existence and removed from the natural
world that they really have no [__]
clue what's happening their brain has
been fused into the digital age and they
don't even know why they do the stuff
they do no
but man my life is like a Elijah's Widow
I I always have what I need I always
have enough and you dude I give freely
of any stranger or anybody God puts in
my path that I feel I'm supposed to help
I can attest to that and there's that's
how I do and guess what if you
if dude much has been given much is
required a body in motion stays at
motion a body at rest stays at rest dude
I'm not a pond I'm a [__] River ponds
get stagnant I'm a river and I let it
flow through me man and hey the bigger I
open my Banks the more that Glacier lets
out and and yeah you see it dude I just
do what he wants me to do okay I
literally mean that and that's and then
whatever the result is it's incumbent on
me to figure out where I'm supposed to
go next if then one Z One
010 and man I
just I'm driven
I am both cursed and blessed to move the
rest of my days until I die if I sit
still if I don't exercise I hurt God I
hurt this computer work has wrecked my
body I'm look look how out of shape I am
I'm it looks terrible and
I I keep doing all this I'll work till
3:45 until I have vertigo around and the
the words or St that's what happened I
literally had couldn't focus I've been
going so hard I drove four hours I met I
shot content I spoke at a real estate
conference spent two hours in the
parking lot came back and now I'm trying
to write this last [__] for the app
because these people will be on the
weekend tomorrow and if I don't do it
now and and Alex said why do you do that
like dude that's a lot of output from
one individual in one day who's already
been doing that same you saw me on the
blocks dude like
the same thing and dude I'm tired God
but this is what I'm here to do and this
is why I've had this training and that's
why Jason Bourne doesn't give a [__] if
he breaks his leg and gets shot in the
side he's just doing his job and until
my job is done I will not stop and this
is part of my job is helping people and
here's the main thing dude change begins
in the minds of
millions and the more I can talk and and
just all I need you to do is hear me
talk one time and guess
what once I get in your head it's hard
to get me
out and that's all I want to do is
incept into people's mind and tell them
things like I've been telling you
because there's nobody else that I know
of saying that and the things that I say
in defiance of [__] regulation and
Liberty fearlessly man people aren't
saying that but dude I'm saying it I'm
right here and I just want more people
to see a little five foot full white boy
speaking out fearlessly and know that
you can do it too and you should do it
and there there's more of Us coming
there's more I will not take it lying
down ever do not take nothing lying down
hey you if you g to lie down you have to
take it on the chin
first that's what I'm saying and I got a
my chin hard to hit and I tell everybody
to be like that man in business and
dealing with regulation and I'm not
saying go out and fight people I'm
telling you you have to stand up for
your right to be and you cannot let this
world change you like that it has
already changed me significantly and I I
can't go back a pickle don't go back to
a
cucumber but the world has a way of
taking a barefooted country boy who just
wants to be left alone in the woods and
turning them into a dark menacing mind
that never shuts
off and you know what happens if you
kick a puppy all the time when he's a
puppy
when he gets bigger he might bite your
ass
and and that's what I mean man and
people need to have that you heal from
your exper whatever dude I don't give a
[__] if you heal or not I want you to
learn and any scar you have any problem
you have in your process in your
business in your life that's what you
need to look at you don't need to be
looking at what you're doing right
unless you're trying to figure out what
you're doing wrong and I think that the
more people realize that they just need
to be honest about themselves to
themselves and to other
people the better they'll do man and
honesty and transparency it's lost in
America that's what one of the things
you said is I love how transparent you
are but now in the digital age you can
put an avatar up there you can change
your makeup you can change your sex you
can change your clothes you can be
whatever you want to be man and you
never ever get to meet a real person
hardly you get get to meet a projection
a representative and and I ain't got
that dog and I wish more people would do
that and especially how does this
pertain to business like I said it's a
three-fold decision one I do it because
that's I love to why does a dog chase a
ball and a horse running the breeze I
understand I don't know if you do I
know number two man it's the it's the
best way to connect with other
humans and that's all we we're social
creature man now have intermediaries you
have to talk through a screen like this
and it's very hard to get personable the
more transparent you are people can tell
it's authentic you connect and then
third in business people never buy a
product they buy the
person and especially if you have an
intangible business like coaching yeah
that's all they're buying all they're
buying is you if you have a if you do
something like that if you're a trainer
you have to have a good body it's I'm
not trusting a skinny Chef or a fat
trainer not
happen um what recharges you cuz I think
I know but like I know you were saying
there there's a lot of there's a lot of
give and out you do what do you do to
recharge that battery that you
have I go to the wild quiet places of
the world yeah I figured that was the
answer hey man dude there's still places
that feel like the Lord of the Rings I
assure you
there's places out there that have a
definite
energy the the Northwoods of Washington
Northeastern Washington below the
Canadian border make me
nervous I'm telling you they do it if it
makes me nervous just being there
imagine what you'd feel like is what I'm
saying and I go out there man and I
think ancient thoughts and I can't tell
you the most regenerative thing cuz I
don't go down into my soul my body is
tough very tough and my mind is pretty
tough but my soul still needs to be
recharged a lot
and the most ancient Sound song in
history dude it's the rhythm of your
feet on the
ground and your heart beating and your
breath and if you ever get to the point
where you do that like I'm talking about
and you realize where you are you'll
start to think the most ancient thoughts
ever and I can't tell you how different
the mind of these people had to have
been never saw a screen never drove a
car never airplane never saw propaganda
a marketing they just existed and they
were so in tuned with
reality and that's what I try to do man
I try I've been spending my whole life
trying to get this noise out of my
[__] head all the [__] that's been
put in there even when I grew up without
a TV I've still been digitally
programmed this is a computer and
they've been uploading it with images
the same way they teach an AI bot dog
your whole life and I got to go get that
out of there and all the time I spend in
the screens takes a toll on me
dude it does the more I look at screens
the worse my it changed my brain the way
it functions the speed at which it
demands information from other people
cuz my brain moves fast and then I
demand information from people as fast
as I get them from my screens because I
interact with them more than I do with
people and I have to
go and I got to go burn off energy dude
if my battery gets high the worst thing
you can do for a lithium batteries let
it sit on charge it'll blow up it's not
made for that you got to expend it and
let it recharge and man that's the other
thing getting my the woods and going to
see my kids
and just seeing my mama and the people
on Sandy Run Court that's like the only
safe place I have in the world right now
like place where I feel safe because you
you could understand why I would be a
little bit a little bit on guard all the
time and it's hard to feel relaxed in
the same way that Frodo never could
relax why because he's on a mission and
he now has this tool that's extremely
powerful and it's guiding him towards
the mission but the more he uses it the
more sick he gets yeah and the heavier
it gets and the more he lashes out at
those around him and like I said hey I'm
doing this Mission and I've been told
what it's going to be
like and and so I'm I'm prepared but it
it's not easy man it's really not easy
to even for somebody like me man to to
keep pushing but but I was told to do
this in my daddy train me quitters never
win and winners never quit pass them on
the hill son all the things my dad told
me just echo in my head and all the
scripture he was the one who read us all
the scriptures all every morning and
every night and we hated it [__]
hated it could not wait to leave hated
God hated the church hated all that but
I didn't understand it I still hate the
church just like Jesus hated them
Pharisee [__] man these that
establishment yeah that's
hey do you think Jesus would ever cut
down a tree to build a CH church or sit
on a cushion Pew in the air conditioning
or Don a
suit no and that's what I'm saying all
they did was they just reprogrammed you
why because now you owe us 10% now we
have a big tax ride off dude it's a it's
a [__] money machine that's all it is
and one of the most recharging things
for me like the blocks was too because I
found a tri vibe that had the same
type I'm not going to say anybody quite
mates my passion but it's in the it's
we're in the same there's a whole lot of
people that get things that you just
don't have to tell them and yeah it was
Unreal for me too it's just like you
understand
me yeah I've been I'm a bobcat and I've
been trying to live with these [__]
Howcast my whole life and then I go out
there and I find some stray ass Angy
cats yeah y'all ain't house cats at all
you ain't quite a [__] Bobcat but hey
I love y'all to death let's go and I
don't sleep a lot either man five I
can't really sleep past six hours ever I
did last night I was tired but but man
the the more I go and the more I do it's
like the more I have to go and I don't
know if it's God driven or Insanity
given but I think the more I accomplish
the more I just crave accomplishment I
don't want money I just want to
accomplish things I used to run six
ultramarathons a year type Joe Fels
running in Google and you'll see all my
race
results I I just go man and you hear
talking to me it's like drinking out of
a fire
right I'm here for it though I'm here
for it and that's the thing I will give
just as freely as I can to anybody given
my time and part of that that has been a
drawback though man I've wasted a lot of
time with insincere people so I know now
especially going to the blocks why they
have monetary filters in place and how
they work and the caliber of people I
need to associate with and things like
that man cuz if you lay down with you
you lay down with other dogs you
probably catch fleas Y and trying to
keep my energy levels with people of the
same caliber and mindset
and I have the idea to build a [__]
fils Village the like an
off-grid little completely repurposed
made out of
trash little Fels Village but you
already know I'm not thinking of just
building a ra right or an Airbnb I'm
thinking about building my concept for
existence into a
village and then just like the Jesus
house I don't know if you've seen the
Jesus
house look up Joe's Jesus house I was
tired of telling people about the man so
I figured if I put it in the house you
could come here and pick up this Vibe
And all I'll tell you is when you first
walk in the door over the Main Kitchen
there's a wooden bird
cage you ever seen a fully wooden bird
cage uh
no yeah pull it up and look at it man
now you're curious I want to see it and
it's you'll see it it's got solid carved
mahogany doors murals of Jesus on the
outside being tempted in the wilderness
and tossing temples or tables in the
Temple oh I
see now go in there and look at that
light
fixture see it over the kitchen it says
book now doesn't where's the
pictures click preview or you click on
the
picture it's not letting me in rentals
maybe I clicked on the wrong one are you
on joe.com
Airbnb okay go to Airbnb oh there we
go got
it okay I see the
fixtures yeah you see that wooden BD
cage yeah the first thing you the first
thing you see when you walk into the
Jesus house is an empty cage is the
light coming on yep it's only now as you
go through this house there's a ton of
Mind Tricks in there there's no TV but
there is a mirror in every room so you
can look at yourself everything's made
out of wood it's antique Peak with stood
the test of time and it's still going
there's a message behind
everything and in that vein I I want to
build a community designed with how I
think life should be where it's
literally designed to have old people
live there why that way the young people
can learn from them generational
learning that's like me learning from
Grandpa when I was a boy and guess what
they also would be the child care while
the people went to work and then the
older people would have a
purpose instead of what they're doing
now and think about how wonderful that
would be for both the parents and the
children instead of a daycare and you
wouldn't have to pay any money right
like just that alone and hey we don't
all need a car we have one big van and
we'll have a little store there too that
stocks Goods that Basics that we need
and we'll buy them in bulk off of Amazon
and you can come in here and get them uh
a greenhouse we're going to have
Hydroponics all cool stuff and a big I
want to have what I call a think space
which is just a big open pole barn where
you can bring hey you you got a broken
dresser you can put it under here and
other people can sit there oh I know how
to fix that and the idea is if you did
that imagine if you had these spread all
out these little communities dude
imagine the sharing of ideas and things
You' You' have I don't know how to fix
that machine or that that engine but
Paul and Minnesota does and yeah and we
can share ideas using technology and
actually try and use this for betterment
and imagine if you could do that and
then get the quality of people I'm
talking about because the type of people
who will be a drawn to this type of
Lifestyle have a different mindset of
what can I put in not what can I get out
and a concentration of those
people living like that amazing it's not
going to be Utopia but what I'm saying
is what could we build what could we
create what could we do can we make a
self-propelling generator that spins for
eternity can we can we figure out a
rainwater drop system that creates more
energy than it uses to pump the water
back up can what can I do what can I do
and how can we be smarter because we're
not worried about all this other
[__] from we're not worried about
oia and we're not worried about IND why
we live out here in the [__] middle
ofwhere we exist and we think and we're
not spending any money we're just living
here we grow our we have everything we
need we don't need your
[__] and that's the kind of idea I'm
going to do next right and think about
it hey if I built that somewhere in
South America when when you build that
would you come would you come visit
I'm but it's not if it's when you build
it I've been busy and and I have to
build the the foundation of this
properly I don't have the ability to to
to manage what managing now effectively
at this moment I've been working on this
machine dude you don't understand guess
what an app will
do see I told you about how wonderful it
is for running your
business but the way I structured it I
will the admin will always have a a
contract with the client and a contract
with the manager okay
and the way that'll work it'll put me on
the general
contractor that means if if you don't
have a license I can pull permits for
you sir
wow and check this out so I have a
selection box in there if you're a
painter and somebody says hey you work
on houses yeah you do roof yeah I do put
it in this app Joe sees it and you know
they select a vendor they say oh Daniel
the painter said I he'll put a roof on
and I see the site visit come in and I
see Daniel the painter is this oh I'm
going to in the roofer to go bid this
job and then we'll put a profit on top
of it if it sells you make the painter
the manager so what I've done is created
a tool where instead of just saying oh
call my buddy you can monetize
it monetize those con Lastly lastly
here's the other thing I'm going to do
because everybody's going to have
insurance I haven't nailed it down yet
I'm looking for an insurance partner
where I can buy a mass policy and then
charge these small handyman people $30 a
week bring in an insurance partner and
also so I have the meeting set I'm
meeting with all of the top brass in the
inspection department at the Jesus house
we're going to clear the air a little
bit and then after that I'm meeting with
uh some Lowe's representatives to
discuss the possibility of opening
everybody up on my manager Network to my
Lowe's
discounts because I get very
advantageous loow not the ones that that
y'all are used to getting I've been
dealing with them for a long time at a
pretty high level and have a great
relationship so the idea would be that
if you're on my manager account you can
submit your material list and we'll get
a quote for it and tell you what we can
get it for and then I'll even buy it on
my account so you don't have to come out
of pocket right then it'll be due when
my bill is due but there's a lot of
incentives for me and then think what
that does to my account managers at
Lowe's and think about that if if Lowe's
is doing that then now would they refer
anybody to this app would the insurance
people refer anybody to this app and
everybody that's in the app are going to
refer people to this
app now take out small business owner
and put investor what if you're flipping
houses and you don't have a builder's
license
I'm boy hey wait a minute what you mean
I can let Joe Fels manage my project for
me yes you can Code Compliance and
professional Consulting is my specialty
and by the way I get things done at that
permit office we have we deal with each
other a lot and we've come to terms so
if I'm pulling permits just imagine how
easy I'm going to make this process for
you at every step man and make it to
where dude like I really built you see
it now yeah you see it It's Like Glue
dude it's glue what we can do is bring
together a massive community of people
who have to this point been competing
against each other we're all direct
competitors yeah but you go you can give
a little and get a little on every frame
and guess what I opened this up we made
permissions worldwide I'm going to be
looking for some Partners in every state
some probably anybody interested in
having a couple thousand dollar a month
monthly stiped and $200 per permit to to
do the same thing and because what would
you do you're going to manage this
project and you're going to you're going
to make sure it's code compliant and
everything when we could really expand
this and make it nationwide
connecting just a massive amount of
people and making it synergistic and
that's the thing me and Eric were
talking about too collaboration beats
competition yes and that's the thing
that's why the business Community is
like it is man but like it's so
competitive and here's the thing I'm a
competitor too and you'd admit I don't
think many people would like to compete
against me much anything and so you know
usually people of that nature who have
an advantage over the competitors
monopolize it but I don't want to do
that I want to take y'all and say hey
little baby bear I've been fishing at
this River a long time let me tell you
how we catch these salmon and then we're
going to have a [__] Army of us
trained all moving in the same direction
which is up that's what I want is a
large community of people who are
actually trying to go forward who are
not they're not crab you know why they
call them crabs step on each other you
ever caught C no hey you if you you ever
go to get a crab out of the bucket right
another crab grab him on the way up he
yeah if you going out I'm going out or
you staying down with me they're crabs
and and we gota first we have to rid
this community of those type of people
and then second we need to get everybody
in there and have the same type of
spirit we had at the blocks
collaborative and understanding that
none of us know anything here step on
step on my hand so you can get up
higher boy I need that my name Nicodemus
come on little old
guy all right so we are almost at the
end here you told us that honestly every
question I was gonna ask you you've
already answered just by us
talking so but can I ask you one thing
absolutely
do my answers seem
unique or very original they are
original just that's what I wanted to
know because I don't I think they're
right just through trial and error but
the main thing is I want to know how
original and unique they are yeah cuz I
I think that they're
very just different man yeah but you
know that by when you ask me certain
questions my answers are different than
what you're going to tell me there's
very few people that have original
thoughts everything's been put in your
head and I never read a I've never I
never read a book on business a book on
investing I've never read bigger poets
I've the only podcast I've ever listened
to was the one I went on with RJ Bates
and then I listen I've listened to my
own and that's it I've never taken in
any outside information to form opinions
been
influenced and then when we my my
business partners and I went through
corporate training they went through it
I didn't go to any of the meetings if
you could believe that I didn't go to
the conference no it was similar to the
blocks but they required all of us to
take a personality
assist and I took one I was back in the
winter and when I was at the blocks and
I was talking to these people and these
very high caliber people were were just
in awe of the things I was telling and
they told me that Brian told me that
he's like when you talk we're in awe
Brian did and to get a compliment from
Brian is and like Dad was like Wow and
I've talked to him mult times after the
vogs we connected he what's it called
but I pulled out the old corporate pi
and and if what my partner told me is
correct I was the most extreme
personality they had ever tested there's
these things called sigmas that I don't
really understand yeah but it's like
it's like something like 3% of the
population has two two high and like a
very small percentage that's three High
I have three that are off the charts and
a fourth one that's super high wow and
then the analysis at the bottom the very
last line said in summary that the
likelihood of you meeting another human
like you on planet Earth is
0.2% so that should tell you your
answers are
unique I know man
but had no confidence for years dude
years it literally when I told you I had
a spiritual experience man that's when
it that's when it started it was in
February of 22 I had no confidence I'd
grown up I'm the only person who's been
through this [__] in my life and all the
messaging I got my entire life at the
base level was you need to
change Church you need to change you're
sinful School you need to be quiet you
need to sit still when I was 13 I made
the cover of focus on the family
magazine for catching two copperheads
bare-handed at a church pic I can send
you the pictures of them if you want
like I have my parents have the magazine
and then rehab and prison and AA and
like your all the mess I got was you're
wrong and you need to change and at some
point I just said [__] no you're
wrong I'm not I got to get this noise
out of my head because I got this in me
and I now I know that I do and that was
the message from God that I got that hit
me like a bolt of lightning and made me
SOB for I ran a 5K back I was in the
middle of a 10K and I started thinking
about this and the thought was about
Stetson Bennett I was thinking about
Stetson and then the thought flashed
across my
soul if you never believe in yourself
you cannot believe in God because God is
within you and it dude and what I can
tell you is I hadn't cried in 13 years
except at my wedding when my wife had to
hold my dad up walking down the aisle
because of the parking other than that
and I I hadn't cried in 13 years and I
saw I started sobbing and I ran 3.1
miles so I'm sobbing running down this
little Road in Country Ass H sobbing I
got back to the house and you can you've
met me imagine me
just and I couldn't tell I couldn't sto
to tell my wife what was going on I went
and laid down in my massive shower I
built for and I couldn't stop sobbing I
could not six months later I'm in a van
headed for the west coast and my entire
life is different and here's what I know
and I I've used this analogy a
bunch think about the difference between
a woman who thinks she's ugly or a woman
who knows she's beautiful or Conor
McGregor when he was 18 and he'd been
fighting and he was a scrapper think
about him then but after he got to the
UFC and he realized that left hand would
put people's lights out even the best in
the world then he became Unleashed he
just understood what he had yeah and he
decided to flaunt it a bit and walk
around on they ass and and that is that
has been the difference for me man just
U check it or respect it man I'm here on
a mission and anything that impedes this
Mission I've got to take on head on
because I don't have time to take the
roundabout
though and I I think that if more people
understand just the the processes to
life they'll do better you have to
understand it down here and then you'll
understand it up here and that applies
so much to business
because this is what's H happens to most
people man and tell me if you
relate you start a business and you see
some level of immediate success you make
some money right and then you keep going
and then you start making a little more
money but it's harder to manage why
because you got all this paper you got
more [__] to do I one of my greatest
philosophers in the 1990s was a man
named Puff Daddy who said More Money
More Problems and he was correct and
what happened is the bigger the machine
gets it it gets shaky because they never
conceived that it would get this big at
the beginning and they laid their
Foundation improper you you can't really
build a second story on top of a a first
story unless the foundation is
engineered properly and in order for you
to make that you have to conceive at the
beginning that this could one time be
massive could be a
skyscraper and structure is so important
and I I just speak in these general
terms because they apply to anybody's
business you have to understand what
you're doing at a core level how the
money enters your business and how it
leaves your business and the the forces
and factors that contribute to money
coming into your business and then you
have to conceive of how you can
positively affect those forces and
factors to your
profit you see how far back we
go you ever seen the movie Inception
yeah I that's a Dream Within A Dream are
goal is to get all the way back there in
in the the very back of our customer or
client's head and place an idea in there
which they will not understand what put
in there but will lead to a uh
predetermined reaction in the
future because whether you know it or
not what's your chief job in business
the most simplest goal in business in
business let's go down to to the look to
the ant smallest particle of business
your chief job solve problem what you
have to do in order to make money sell
the product no I said solve a problem
solve a problem okay but what is the
problem but here's the deal your Chief
end is to get a person to do what you
want them to
do whether it's your somebody to buy the
product or somebody to click on your
website or your girlfriend to stop
talking or your kids to clean up their
room or the person in the tag office to
not give a [__] about the dots and the
te's you're trying to convince another
human to do what you want them to do but
the problem is you can't just force it
on right because they have Inception has
to be their they have defense mechanism
and so you have to be very Innovative
and when you talk to a person I don't
know if you notice but I'll talk to them
and I'm going to be looking right
through and the things that I say and do
are all to a certain end and it's very
obscure and most people pretty much none
of them ever have a clue until it's
already they they don't even know that
it's been placed there but it has and
that's my chief goal man and God has me
doing it on social media now and I think
I'm doing a decent job of getting my
message out there despite all the
censorship and I used to do it with
business I could sell I can sell a job
really well and and I think I could I
don't want to I don't want to but I
think I should take on politics Mayor
run for mayor of Augusta why do I want
to be a mayor no but I would love to be
able to talk like this at a forum that
is much higher than social
media because ven could you
imagine what it would be like to have a
politician
[Laughter]
debating I know they can't
imagine they might not know it but I'm a
master Dee
I'm here to tell you dog uh and that's
what I'm saying man I just want to be
able to explain things in the way that I
view them and with the goal of not
necessarily becoming mayor but if I
actually ran for mayor and did it do I
think it would make National headlines
because of the [__] that I would
do literally Mr Fels you have to wear a
shirt a it must be collared you're in
you know like
and when just the things that I would do
man and what is my goal to make life
better for people because that's my
chief complaint man and and I got so mad
last week or the week before I sent
emails to this every the highest level
of government I could the city
administrator and she referred me higher
than her nobody wants to talk to me code
enforcement the number two the City
attorney the manager of the building
inspection department because what
happened is I there was a man there and
I'll just preface it a little bit he's
been to prison before he's been out for
a long time he started a company he
makes his own flooring and I helped him
learn how to invest in real estate and
he set up a $400,000 line of
credit he's a black man he's my homie
love him to death and he bought a house
and they he was inside his house talking
to his real estate agent Richmond County
Code Enforcement walks in the door and
begins taking pictures pictures and he
says hey what are you doing you can't be
here and they said no you can't be here
you're working without a permit and they
and he stopped he said no you can't go
back that you got to go you got to talk
to the owner you can't be here and this
man called me frantically they put a on
the
door
and and he he called me nine times he
didn't get any sleep he's worried sick
and I've been in his position multiple
times I know how he feels it literally
feels like you caught a charge that's
how it feels
and so my question was this where I
emailed all these people and have yet to
receive a response is can you please
provide me with the laws codes statutes
Etc that provide Richmond County Code
Enforcement the authority to enter a
private residence without a warrant and
begin gather Gathering evidence and the
procedures handling any such evidence
gathered in this
manner because the code enforcement
officer told me that she saw men inside
saw the door was open and she just went
in and I asked her how she had the
authority to do that without a warrant
and then she told me that it was there
was no expectation of privacy in a
vacant structure and I said you just
told me you saw people inside now it's
vacant which one was it wow and she told
me it was federal law that she could do
this and I have all this documented and
she also told me that she had met the
owner there previously before on a prior
occasion and when I went to get the
permits they charged they're charging me
because I have to pay it which is very
interesting wrinkle gives me a little
bit of standing
$1,500 for $1,500 in fines and so when I
get back to Augusta I don't know what
they do with this but I understand what
a Freedom of Information Act is and I'd
like to know how much money they bring
in and where it goes and a couple of
other little details and what I'm saying
is I'm fixing to start asking some
important questions
that they probably are not prepared to
answer because they have very awkward
answers like how fat is your mom and
dad the City attorney hung up on
me still have an
answer yeah and what I'm saying is I
told him I was looking I spent a lot of
time read all I found was this fourth
amendment I don't know maybe the house
police have more Authority than the
regular police that they can literally
just enter your property take pictures
tell you to leave and you have to pay
him before you come back to your
property he owes no man a dollar on this
property and that's what gets me insens
this is my friend I have never taken a
dollar from him for coaching or anything
he just called me to help him I'm a
contractor and I'm ready to put my body
on the line with the city of Augusta for
an ideal that a [__] should be
able to exist in his four walls and do
what the [__] he
wants and I'm going to keep screaming
that at the top of my lungs and saying
check it or respect yeah that's how I
feel and I might play by your little
[__] rules right now but I disagree
and I'm starting to vocalize it and if
you're going to govern me I am not going
to be easy to govern in fact I have an
idea $1,500 no problem I saw on the
penny that this is legal tender for all
debts public and private
[Music]
I also have a
wheelbarrow
coins just some ideas and here's what
I'm saying you write the rules I just
read them dog and if you want to treat
me like this I'm going to treat you the
same way I'm going to read and nitpick
dude I told him I'm going to send him a
certified letter every time I find a
blade of grass in the city that's over
12 longer than 12 Ines cuz that's what
they do to me I'm just give them hell
dude and they're just this is prison I
can't leave here yet I'm still here and
if you're going to try and Bully me I'm
gonna give you every reason on planet
Earth to go pick somebody
else and if more people have that with
customers and everything you can't just
go out and I wish you could just fight
them I really wish you could but you
have to learn to remember your chief
goal is to convince somebody to do what
you want and these people don't listen
to nothing else and if you want to make
money in business all you have to do is
learn to cut regulation that's it yeah
well Joe this has been an exhilarating
conversation we're gonna have to a lot
we're gonna have to cut this one we can
do another one at another point but um
yeah I appreciate everything that you've
done I appreciate the exhilarating
conversation and answers to the
questions even before I ask
them hey that's what I'm going to tell
you man lastly the book of AI all these
books they said basically the way that
humans have determined intelligence for
our entire existence is how fast can an
intelligence come to an accurate
conclusion with limited
data and that's the thing it becomes a
six sense the algorithm is really good
because it it thinks something and if
it's wrong it all it never forgets it it
always remembers its mistake and it goes
back there again it shuts that off you
ever been shadowbanned on Facebook now
why made a decision something happened I
don't know what
but you know that uh that's how my brain
works man like literally if you start
talking about something I will want to
complete your sentence you watch me I
have to hold it
back if you ever play me in chess you
take as long as you want as I'll wait as
soon as you move that piece I'm gone
yeah
thinking about every possible step of
every possible if then is a really good
way to to try to view everything man and
I'm excited to see what I'll do with
this because God has told me that I have
a he's given me a special gift and and I
got to learn how to use it you do have
when I could use it for good or use it
for evil you do have a gift and I you're
you're using it for good already where
can people find
you in this
van man the if you ever want to get to
me we're about done VY what's
wrong if you ever want to get to me the
the best way would be Fels mediagroup
dorg contct us okay I could give you my
cell phone where's my cell phone no they
they can get no I have 1,800 Miss call
okay I have 1800 I just mean your hand
SC yeah so your handles on Instagram you
Joe fails across all platforms except
Facebook because my account got disabled
randomly yeah a few days ago no nothing
hey you know what's crazy we went back I
my account was disabled at 658 a.m. at
7:04 a.m. I got a payment from Facebook
H what okay and my Instagram is still
there and the guy they said I've never
heard of this it said it was like
Paramount tour some weird name that it
said I was linked to with on meta and I
don't know okay but Joe FS if you type
it in Google just type Joe Fs in Google
and you can find them and if and I'll
show you guys the house like when I post
this so you can see what the Jesus house
looks like and and again thank you tell
Alex we said hello and what one last
thing guys if anybody sees this podcast
when and wants to when people see this
if anybody when you see this podcast if
you want to travel to any of my Airbnb
Joe's Jesus house Joe's SE Shack or
Joe's tree Retreat don't instant book
send me a message or request to book
prior and mention this podcast and I
will give you a 20% discount off your
lodging
fees there you go and Joe's Jesus house
is in Augusta Georgia it's across from
Lake Alstead right across the street
from a disc golf course half a mile from
the running and jogging trails there's a
rope swing Savannah River about a mile
from the Augusta National
Joe's tree Retreat is in Tennessee it's
a half mile off the Appalachian Trail
and Wataga Lake you can walk straight
through the forest be on the trail at
the lake in seven minutes Smoky Mountain
Retreat and then Joe seashack Olympic
Peninsula a little town I call squish
squim Washington 9 minutes from the
beach 15 minutes from Olympic National
Park in a town with legal cannabis fresh
hbit fresh tuna dungeoness crab and my
neighbor Gary who grew up in Alaska and
has been their for 47 years and will
come light a fire for you if it's cold
at night come check out any of these man
and I just love to link and meet people
yeah that then that's those are
Priceless experiences but you heard it
Joe said he'll give you 20% off if you
mention credit chats just contact him
and for all of these wonderful locations
you can find them on Airbnb and just
find them but but yeah thank you again
Joe like I said tell Alex we said hello
and everybody that's another credit chat
thank
you boom
whoa whoa whoa were you about to leave
without hitting that like And subscribe
button I mean you'll be back right so
why not save yourself the hassle and
just do it now it's like putting your
keys by the door or packing your lunch
or packing three days before your flight
and not the night of it just makes life
easier oh wait did did did you just do
it I knew you had it in you I appreciate
that see you next time same place same
Channel and remember everything you need
is inside of you